残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても
私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっと触れるもの 求めることに夢中で
運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の帝世 窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
おとばしる熱いパトスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
ご視聴ありがとうございました
初めての工場に 恐れるものと
簡単に誘うお値しください
ご視聴ありがとうございました
ちゃんと祝аковを版 like
されたら 有賊はあり返し
その通りに確認 對し
That will be blocked any day now.
So should I do something about that project as well?
No. Judging by the material you sent me, it appears there will be no need.
Then I'll proceed with the plan.
Uh, good morning.
Good morning.
That's the way to start your morning.
What's wrong with coffee?
You got a problem with tradition?
Don't you know that a traditional Japanese breakfast is steamed rice, miso soup, and a little sake?
Your tradition, maybe.
Excuse me?
And incidentally, just whose turn was it supposed to be to cook today?
Well, now I know why a woman your age is still single.
You're going to be an old maid, miso.
Are you saying that I'm lazy?
And sloppy, too.
Oh, just leave me alone.
Oh, I'm finished.
So, are you really coming to my school today?
Of course I am.
It's your parent-teacher meeting.
But you're just so busy at work.
Oh, it's no problem.
You're part of my job anyway.
Well, it's just part of your job, huh?
Hi!
Oh, thanks for coming.
Yes, he's getting ready.
I'll come let you in.
Misato, you shouldn't go outside dressed like that.
It's embarrassing.
I know.
Good morning, Ikari.
Thanks, Misato.
We're taking off now.
Be careful.
Oh, come on.
Ironic.
The way he's getting more casual and expressing his feelings is a good trend.
Yes, he's just left.
Make sure you keep your eyes on him.
Yeah!
Oh, she really came!
Is she Ikari's guardian?
What?
He's got a babe like that for a bodyguard?
Look at those idiots.
Oh, Misato is so gorgeous.
Yeah, right.
It's amazing someone so beautiful could be Nerve's operations director.
I don't think so.
Huh?
Hey, Kensuke.
It's a good thing that Shinji is such a baby.
Yeah, he's no rival for us.
You guys don't know what a slob she is.
Man, I wish Misato were my girlfriend.
Oh, no, you don't.
You just don't get it, do you?
Okay, you can handle keeping the Earth safe, and the two of us will take care of Misato.
Unit 1 has achieved the required cooling level.
Shifting operations to stage 2.
Keeping the Earth safe.
That's what Eva's for.
Come to think of it, just what is Eva?
This entry plug smells a lot like blood.
But I feel so comfortable and relaxed here.
Now that I think of it, I don't know anything about it.
What's the status of Unit 0's bio-chest components?
It was seriously damaged, so we'll have to make an entirely new one, even though it's pretty close to our ancillary budget's limits.
Will our job get any simpler once we get Unit 2 from Germany?
It could go just the other way.
Disposing of those dead angels costs a bundle.
Yeah, this place is ridiculously underfinanced, especially since mankind's future rests on us.
It can't be helped.
Man cannot live by Eva alone.
All those survivors need money to live, too.
Money, money, money.
So is the commander off to another conference again?
Yes, he's on board and in route now.
Thank God for a little peace and quiet.
Excuse me, do you mind if I sit here?
Go ahead.
The revised budget for the sample collection passed quite easily, didn't it?
The committee's main concern is for their own survival.
They won't be so budget conscious when their own lives are at stake.
Yes, they used to think they were no more angels.
And I have more good news.
All the permanent members of the Security Council, except the United States, have approved the budget for AVA Unit 6.
It's just a matter of time before the U.S. approves it as well.
The Americans seem to be allergic to unemployment, but they'll learn.
And your country?
We will participate in the construction beginning with Unit 8.
The plans for the second installation project are still viable.
However, a pilot has not yet been found.
The Angels have returned.
We will have no other choice but to defeat them.
My people do not want a repeat of the second impact either.
You understand that.
You mean that everything I've learned about second impact is wrong?
Yes.
The history books say that it was a disaster caused by a massive meteorite.
But most of the true facts have been concealed through international government cover-ups.
Fifteen years ago, in Antarctica, mankind discovered the being known as the first angel.
In the middle of the investigation, however, for unknown reasons, the angel exploded.
That is the real truth about the second impact.
Then the things we're doing here are...
Are to prevent a probable third impact before it happens.
That is the sole purpose of Nerve and the Evangelions.
By the way, Masato, the event will occur tomorrow as scheduled.
I understand.
Good morning.
Good morning, Masato.
I'm going to old Tokyo on business.
I'll probably be getting back late tonight, so have something delivered for dinner.
Bye.
Okay.
Um, sure.
It's hard to believe that this place used to be the flourishing capital known as Tokyo.
We're here.
Hmm?
Why are they having this in a place like this?
Is the SSDF getting involved?
The Strategic Self-Defense Force?
No.
They're not allowed to interfere.
I see.
That's why they can do whatever they like.
Thank you.
I'd like to thank you all for coming to this special demonstration of Japan Heavy Chemical Industrial Cooperative's latest product.
In a few minutes, we'll be taking you up to the control room to observe the actual demonstration.
But first, we'll be answering some of your questions here.
Yes.
Ah, the famous Dr. Ritsuko Akagi.
It's our pleasure to have you here for this demonstration.
Thank you.
May I ask you a question?
Of course.
Certainly.
The unit is equipped with an internal nuclear reactor.
Is this correct?
Correct.
This is our product's most distinguished feature, guaranteeing 150 days of continuous operating power.
I see.
But from a safety perspective, isn't it rather risky to incorporate a nuclear reactor in a land-based weapon designed for hand-to-hand combat?
We think it's more practical than a weapon that won't work for more than five minutes.
But in an emergency, there would be problems with remote control.
But it's more humane than a system that induces tremendous mental stress and causes mental instability in the pilot.
Quiet out.
You're acting like children.
And there's still the issue of manual control.
I would think that it is much safer than an extremely dangerous weapon that's been known to run out of control and go berserk in the middle of a city.
A weapon that cannot be controlled is insane.
It's like an hysterical woman.
Completely out of control.
Our technology will be able to control it.
So you're saying that science and human courage will tame the savage Ava beast?
Are you serious?
Yes, of course I'm serious.
And because it depends on something as fragile as a human heart, NERV has allowed the situation to get completely out of control.
The UN has already had to approve an enormous supplement to your existing budget.
And as a result, 20,000 people in a dozen countries are starving to death.
Of course, the actual cause of all this is still under investigation.
Why don't you at least take responsibility for your handiwork?
How fortunate that your organization is above the law.
It doesn't matter what you say.
The fact is that NERV has the only weapon capable of defeating the enemy.
You mean the AT field.
That is simply a matter of time and research.
NERV's day in the sun will not last forever.
Damn him!
Those jokes are just pissed off about being cut out of their share of the loot!
I want to rip off that smug face of his and shove it into this locker!
Then I'll kick it and kick it and kick it!
Put that out.
Behave yourself.
He's just a show-off, begging for praise and adulation.
He's petty, not worthy of attention.
Yeah, but how did that smug SOB know about the AT field?
How could something so classified leak out?
Intelligence must be dragging its ass.
We are ready to begin the jet alone activation test.
Don't worry, folks.
There is no risk at all.
Please, make yourselves comfortable and watch through the observation window.
We are ready to begin.
Let's start the test.
Discharging the power core.
Pressure levels normal.
Coolant system circulation normal.
Release the control rods.
The reactor has reached nominal power status.
Output is normal.
Begin walk cycle.
Walking forward ahead.
Slow.
Forward right leg.
Roger.
Walk.
Forward ahead slow.
Forward right leg.
Balance is nominal.
Power core status nominal.
Roger.
Now, forward left leg.
Keep us steady.
Roger.
Forward left leg.
Maintaining balance.
Oh, boy.
It's walking.
That's certainly something to be proud of.
Wow.
What's wrong?
This is odd.
The pressure inside the reactor is increasing.
The temperature of the primary cooling system is also rising.
Valve open.
Insert the neutron deceleration fluid.
No effect.
The pump output isn't increasing.
Initiating valve system check.
All right.
Emergency stop.
Cut off the power.
Abort signal transmission confirmed.
It's not accepting it.
The radio circuit is being blocked.
It's out of control.
This can't be happening.
It's coming right at us.
Oh, my God.
This robot's as badly behaved as the idiot who built it.
The compression valve is operating irregularly.
The control rods aren't working.
Possibility of meltdown imminent.
Impossible.
The jet alone's onboard computer system has been programmed to handle all possible contingencies
and scenarios.
This kind of thing simply cannot happen.
Well, then, you're about to have an impossible nuclear meltdown out there.
Under the present circumstances, our only viable option is to wait for it to stop itself.
And how likely is that?
0.0002%.
It would be an act of God.
Acts of men are better than acts of God.
Tell me how to stop that thing.
We've already tried every possible option.
Not yet.
There's got to be a last resort.
A way to wipe out everything.
Tell me the password.
The password to delete all programming is top secret.
I don't have the authority to release it.
I'm sorry, but I'm not allowed to tell you.
Then you better get the clearance, Vato.
Do it!
Tukita here.
Let me speak to Mr. Manda in Tokyo, too.
That's right.
The Director of Internal Affairs.
Well, I'll have to delegate that to Mr. Yasugi.
Ask him.
Well, I can't give you authorization for such an important matter verbally.
Could you submit a written request?
So now I need to get Mr. Yoshizawa's permission?
What?
Yes, I've already gotten approval from Mr. Witts.
Yes.
Okay.
Bureaucracies.
A written order of clearance will be sent.
I'll give you the password then.
We can't wait that long!
Watch Jettelone's reactor red lines.
It'll be too late.
Jettelone is heading for Atsugi City.
Time's running out.
I'm taking the responsibility for this operation myself.
You can wait here.
Yuga, I want you to roll out the transport and bring Shinji and Unit 1 with the F equipment
up here right now.
Yes, this is an emergency.
This is pointless.
Call this off, Captain Katsuragi.
Do you have any idea as to how to stop it?
I'll override the computer manually.
Are you serious?
Yes.
But Jettelone's interior must be flooded with radiation.
You're insane.
But if I succeed, Atsugi will be saved.
The access hatch can be opened manually as soon as our command signal is cut off.
You should be able to enter the hatch through the backpack unit.
Mm-hmm.
Hope.
That's the password to delete the programming.
Thank you, sir.
Our target is Jettelone.
There's a danger that it may begin to melt down in five minutes.
Therefore, we cannot allow it to get any closer to a populated area.
Yuga.
Yes, ma'am.
As soon as you drop Unit 1, take the transport up to a safe altitude and stand by.
Roger.
And Shinji.
Yes.
Run alongside the target and place me onto its back.
Once I've gotten on, I want you to try to hold Jettelone back as much as you can.
You're climbing on that thing?
To break into it?
That's right.
But that's just crazy.
I know.
But I'm afraid there just isn't any better way to stop it.
But it's too dangerous.
Don't worry.
Unit 1's armor can handle both the explosion and the radiation.
Not for Ava.
I meant for you.
Well, I've got to give it my best shot, you know.
My conscience won't let me do otherwise.
Ma'am, I've sighted the target.
Right.
Here we go.
Ava approaching drop position.
Docking release.
Roger.
We caught up with it.
We've got less than four minutes.
Put me on now.
Don't think about it.
Do it.
Misano.
I found it.
Error?
What the hell?
The program must have been altered.
It must have.
The power reactor is just 0.2 point short of critical.
The control rod still won't function.
I guess I'll try the long shot.
Misano!
Get out of there!
I'm so scared.
Dammit!
Die!
I'm so scared.
Misano!
0.1 to critical.
My God, it's going to go.
Meltdown imminent.
All safety's failing.
Dear God.
Misano!
She did it!
Internal pressure lowering.
All readings are nominal.
Yes!
Yes, she did it!
Crazy fool.
Misato, are you all right?
Misato!
Yeah, I'm okay.
Not in the greatest of shape, however.
You're alive!
Oh, God!
Are you all right?
Oh, thank God!
I can't believe you did it!
It's a miracle!
Yeah, but the miracle was set up by someone.
Recovery of Unit 1 is completed.
No danger of radioactive contamination.
Except for Captain Katsuragi's operation.
Everything went according to the plan.
Good work.
Good morning, Shinji.
That's the way to start your morning.
Now, let me out that shower.
Hey, Shinji, have you seen any clean bras or panties lying around?
Good morning, Ikari!
Hmm?
Morning.
I'm taking off!
Have a nice day!
Misato is just so cool.
Yeah, I used to think so, too.
But she's such a slob.
She's always embarrassing me.
She never does anything but lie around the house.
She's not embarrassed about it, but I am.
You're a lucky guy.
What do you mean?
Ikari really is just a kid, isn't he?
He sure is.
Meaning what?
She let you see a side of her that she wouldn't show to anyone else, right?
That means she's your family.
Yeah.
Fly me to the moon and let me play among the stars.
Let me see what's bling is like on Jupiter and Mars.
In other words, hold my hand.
In other words, darling, kiss me.
Be my heartless song and let me sing forever more.
You are all I long for, all I worship and adore.
In other words, please be true.
In other words, I love you.
Get ready to meet Eva Unit 2 and its pilot as they head towards Japan.
Will Shinji be able to handle this loud and pushy redhead?
Or is his ship already sunk?
Things get worse when a new angel surprise attack forces them to activate Unit 2 in the Eva's first undersea battle.
Don't miss, Asuka strikes!